// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "A trader sells wheat at 20% profit and uses 20% less than the actual measure. His gain % is?",
    answer: "50",
    options: ["35%", "50%", "38%", "45%"],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question:
      "At what percentage above the Cost Price must an article be marked so that after giving 5% discount a shopkeeper may gain 33% of profit.",
    answer: "40%",
    options: ["43%", "40%", "48%", "45%"],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question:
      "A and B started a business together and got a profit in the ratio 3 ∶ 5. If B invested ₹80,000 for 12 months, then A invested ₹72,000 for how many months?",
    answer: "8 Months",
    options: ["10 Months", "9 Months", "8 Months", "6 Months"],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question:
      "The marked price of an article is Rs. 180. Radhika sells it after 20% discount on its market price and still gain 25%. The cost price (in Rs.) of the article is:",
    answer: "115.20",
    options: ["110.80", "115.20", "125.50", "120.80"],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question:
      "A shopkeeper earns a profit of 25 percent on selling a radio at 15 percent discount on the Printed price. Finds the ratio of the Printed price and the cost price of the radio.",
    answer: "25:17",
    options: ["17:25", "25:27", "27:25", "25:17"],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question:
      "Two successive discounts of 40% and 20%, respectively, on the marked price of an article are equal to single discount of Rs 988. The marked price (in Rs) of the article is:",
    answer: "1900",
    options: ["1900", "2200", "2470", "2070"],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question:
      "Sulekha bought 36 kg of sugar for Rs. 1,040. She sold it at a profit equal to the selling price of 10 kg of it. What is the selling price (in Rs.) for 5 kg of sugar ?",
    answer: "200",
    options: ["200", "215", "220", "235"],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "Amar sells his TV at a rate of Rs. 1540 and bears a loss of 30%. At what rate should he sell his TV so that he gains a profit of 30%?",
    answer: "2860",
    options: ["2920", "2480", "2680", "2860"],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question:
      "Peter started a retail business by investing Rs. 25000. After eight months Sam joined him with a capital of Rs. 30,000. After 2 years they earned a profit of Rs. 18000. What was the share of Peter in the profit?",
    answer: "10000",
    options: ["12000", "16000", "10000", "20000"],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question:
      "A TV set is being sold for Rs. X in Delhi. A dealer went to Chandigarh and bought the TV at 20% discount (from the price of Delhi). He spends Rs. 600 on transport. Thus, he sold the set in Delhi for Rs. X making (100/7) % profit what is the value of X?",
    answer: "8000",
    options: [
      "7200",
      "8000",
      "8800",
      "9600",
    ],
  },
];
